The magic beneath us
Fantastic Fungi is a documentary film directed by Louie Schwartzberg.
A vivid journey into the mysterious subterranean world
of mycelium and its fruit— the mushroom.
A story that begins 3.5 billion years ago, fungi makes the soil that supports life, connecting vast
systems of roots from plants and trees all over the planet, like an underground Internet.
Through the eyes of renowned mycologist Paul Stamets, professor of forest ecology Suzanne Simard, best selling author Michael
Pollan, food naturalist Eugenia Bone and others, we experience the power, beauty and complexity of the fungi kingdom.
Narrator (voice), played by Brie Larson.
Self, played by Paul Stamets.
Self, played by Michael Pollan.
Self, played by Roland Griffiths.
Self, played by Andrew Weil.
Self, played by Mary P. Cosmiano.
Fantastic Fungi is a 2019 American documentary
film directed by Louie Schwartzberg.
The film combines time-lapse cinematography, CGI, and interviews in an overview
of the biology, environmental roles, and various uses of fungi.
The film features interview segments with Paul Stamets and
Michael Pollan, and is narrated by Brie Larson.
The film explores themes of nature, science, fungi.
The tone is lighthearted and thought_provoking.